Jason Coles

jasonrcoles@gmail.com • 503.841.9322 • www.linkedin.com/in/jasoncolespdx

ABOUT ME

Delivers customer value through relationship building and product expertise. Enjoys being a trusted advisor to the customer by identifying solutions to potential problems, striving to be a product expert and taking on the role of the voice of the customer to others in the organization. Great communication and decision-making skills allow me to contribute throughout an organization. Proven multitasking ability and develop and improve processes to help meet the overall goals through upselling opportunities and increase customer adoption.

SKILLS INVENTORY

Customer Service Experienced Trainer Time Management Attention to Detail Verbal & Written Communication Cross-Functional **Team Collaboration** Creative Problem Solving **Process Improvement Conflict Resolution** Account Management **Event Management Event Venue Coordination Operations Management** Financial Tracking & Reporting Inventory Tracking & Control

Cross-Cultural Communication TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY IN

MS OFFICE {WORD, EXCEL, POWERPOINT} | SALESFORCE | POINT-OF-SALE SOFTWARE

EDUCATION

Quality Control

Records Management

University of Nevada, Las Vegas | Las Vegas, NV | BS | Hotel Administration | 1996 Portland State University Lean Certificate | 2018

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

SENIOR AIRMAN • 1989 -1993

UNITED STATES AIR FORCE

Wright-Patterson AFB, Ohio

Achievements:

Medical Squadron, 1st Quarter – Airman of the Quarter, 1991 AF Commendation Medal, 1993

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- Received a 97% success rating as Implementation Specialist at Crescent Systems, managed successful training of employees at more than 100 golf courses inperson and on-line with tight deadlines with limited resources
- Innovative problem solving and development of new training materials to meet a wide variety of customer abilities
- Trusted and experienced communicator in relaying customer needs between multiple departments.

EXPERIENCE

TRANSPORTATION COORDINATOR • 2015 – June 2018

CHARLIE'S PRODUCE • Wholesale Produce Company • Clackamas, OR

Competency Highlights:

Fleet Dispatch Supervise the daily dispatch of 30 to 50 vehicles and drivers delivering to 250 to 700 locations per day.

Customer Service Provided Charlie's team members and clients guidance, support and direction through phone, email, and online applications increasing overall satisfaction for internal and external customers

Innovation | Process Improvement Introduced systems to improve delivery and tracking processes. Continuously monitor processes to refine system efficiency.

Training Curriculum Development Overhauled and developed new training materials and methods to improve driver training and customers service.

Data Analysis Implemented system to analyze data to fine-tune and streamline the delivery process, increase profit and eliminate waste.

TOURNAMENT AND EVENT SALES/COORDINATOR • 2004 – 2014 **STONE CREEK GOLF COURSE** • Public Golf Course • Oregon City, OR

Competency Highlights:

Sales/Managed Sold and Managed more than \$750,000 in business each year. **Customer Service** Exceeded customer service expectations through attention to detail, innovation and excellent organization.

Communication Provided clients excellent guidance, support and direction in person and through phone, email, and online applications.

Event Management Developed processes and guidelines for successful and efficient tournament operations.

Staff Training & Delegation Managed event staffing, training and assigned tasks for team members to ensure smooth event operations.

Process Improvement Created new documents and internal guidelines to assist in the organization of tournaments/events and thorough follow up.

IMPLEMENTATON SPECIALIST • 1999 – 2004

CRESCENT SYSTEMS, INC. • Golf Course/Club Mgmt. Software • Libertyville, IL *Competency Highlights:*

Venue Coordination Coordinated and trained in over 100 private, public, dinning clubs and gun clubs throughout the USA and Guam.

Innovation | Process Improvement Generated high level of comprehension through innovative and pertinent training.

Training Curriculum Development Developed easy-to-use training materials to address staffs with differing levels of software and learning competency.

Time Management Overcame training obstacles in active work environments through excellent time management and adaptation.

Software Coordination Worked with development teams to improve our suite of golf software solutions to over 200 facilities. Software facilitated multiple functions, including tee sheet, point-of-sale, inventory control, food & beverage/fine dining and accounting.